https://www.msvu.ca/academics/university-academic-calendars/undergraduate-academic-calendar/regulations/2-2-29-privacy-of-information/

Home » Academics » University Academic Calendars » Undergraduate Academic Calendar » Regulations » 2.2.29 Privacy of Information
2.2.29 Privacy of Information
Show Show Section Menu
Academics
Bachelor of Arts (BA)
Caregiving
Health Human Resources (Home Support Workers)
Health Human Resources (Future Home Care Needs)
Library
Modern Languages (Chinese, French and Spanish)
Program Requirements (French)
Program Requirements (Spanish)
Club français / French Club
Expand Your World Program (NEW!)
SOAN Adjunct Faculty Profile
Get Involved!
ENGL & WRIT Courses
Bachelor of Science (BSc)
Courses
Interested in Honours?
Organization of Conferences and Symposia
Book: Quantum Biochemistry (2010)
The Quantum Theory of Atoms in Molecules (2007)
Jennifer Thornton
Ready for Statistics (MATH 2208)?
IEP Sponsor Information
Food Action Research Centre (FoodARC)
Bachelor of Business Administration
New Masters of Public Relations program at MSVU!
Tourism and Hospitality Management
New Masters of Public Relations program at MSVU!
Faculty of Education
Bachelor of Education (Elementary/Secondary)
2.1.4.5 Non-Degree Students
2.1.5 Holders of University Degrees, Diplomas and Certificates
2.1.6 Additional Admissions Requirements
2.1.7 Students With Disabilities
2.1.8 Audit
2.1.9 Preparation for Professional Programs
2.1.10 Status Upon Admission to Bachelor of Arts or Bachelor of Science
2.1.11 Principles Governing the Awarding of Multiple Credentials
Regulations
2.2.1 Applying External Credits
2.2.2 Transfer Credits
2.2.3 Letter of Permission (LOP)
2.2.15 Transcripts
2.2.16 Co-Curricular Record (CCR)
2.2.22.1 Grade Appeals
2.2.22.2 Appeal of Misapplication of University Regulations by Petition to the Committee on Academic Appeals
2.2.23.3 Other
2.2.23.4 Procedures for Dealing with Plagiarism, Cheating, and Other Academic Offences
2.2.5 Thesis Requirement
2.2.6 Letter of Permission (LOP)
2.2.15.1 Grade Appeals
2.2.15.2 Appeal of Misapplication of University Regulations by Petition to the Committee on Academic Appeals
2.2.16.3 Other
2.2.16.4 Procedures for Dealing with Plagiarism, Cheating and Other Academic Offences
Co-operative Education at the Mount
Co-op in the Business Administration Program: “Worth Every Single Minute”
Six Simple Steps to Co-op Success
Soaring to New Heights – Finding Confidence and Clarity through Internship
Taking my Degree Down Under
Where are they now?
Tourism Alumnae Maureen Mix, BTHM '91
Where are they now?
The Employer Perspective
My Time with J.D. Irving Ltd.
Making Childhood Dreams a Reality
Strong Women Work Here: National PR Firm Values Creativity, Collaboration and Fun
Student Spotlight: Cassie Pilon
PR student gains diverse communications experience and mentorship in federal government
Services
Library F.A.Q.
Library Services for Distance Courses
Request/Update an ID Card (online form)
2020-2021 Academic Year
Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy (FOIPOP) In 1993, the province of Nova Scotia enacted the Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy Act. Its purpose is to make public bodies more open and accountable to the public in the way they acquire, use and dispose of information.
This is achieved in a number of ways including:
giving the public a right of access to records in the custody and control of the University, subject only to limited and specific exemptions;
giving individuals a right of access to personal information held by the University about them and allowing them the opportunity to request a correction to said information;
specifying limited exemptions to the right of access;
ensuring appropriate collection, use and disclosure of personal information.
The Act also provides the opportunity for individuals to request information, making public bodies directly accountable to each citizen.
A complete copy of the Nova Scotia Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy Act is available on the government web site at https://oipc.novascotia.ca/legislation.
Personal Information and Protection of Electronic Documents (PIPEDA)PIPEDA, which came into force January 1, 2001, establishes new rules for privacy. The rules recognize the rights of individuals to control the use of their personal information. The rules also impose obligations on organizations to protect personal information in a manner that a reasonable person would consider appropriate in the circumstances. This legislation protects the privacy rights of all Canadians as it applies to every organization that collects, uses or discloses personal information in the course of commercial activities.
A complete copy of Bill C-6, the Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act is available on the Privacy Commissioner’s web site at https://www.priv.gc.ca/en/privacy-topics/privacy-laws-in-canada/the-personal-information-protection-and-electronic-documents-act-pipeda/.
Privacy ActUnder the federal Privacy Act, individuals can request access to their own individual information held in federal information banks, including those held by Statistics Canada.
Notification of Disclosure of Personal Information to the Maritime Provinces Higher Education Commission (MPHEC)
The MPHEC collects student identification information (student’s name, student ID number), student contact information (address and telephone number), student demographic characteristics, and enrolment information from Mount Saint Vincent University.
Enrolment and demographic information is used by MPHEC in the preparation of basic statistics, as well as to understand student pathways through to graduation, and the factors that affect these pathways. The information assists governments and Mount Saint Vincent University in decision-making and in enhancing the post-secondary learning environment.
Personally-identifying information is used only for limited purposes:
To create record linkages between data from different Mount Saint Vincent University in order to track student pathways among Mount Saint Vincent University. Once records are linked, personal information is deleted from the research data file.
To communicate with Mount Saint Vincent University and Statistics Canada during the data validation process. Compile a student/graduate contact list for an MPHEC survey
The legal authority for these activities is provided by a data sharing agreement between Mount Saint Vincent University and the MPHEC, as well as the Maritime Provinces Higher Education Commission Act. The Act requires that all data received by the Commission is kept confidential, and ensures the protection of personal information. More information about the MPHEC may be found at www.mphec.ca. A copy of its Standard for Maintaining Confidentiality is available here: http://www.mphec.ca/general/confidentiality.aspx
Questions may be addressed to:
Director, Research and Data AnalysisMaritime Provinces Higher Education Commission82 Westmorland St. Suite 401PO Box 6000Fredericton NB E3B 5H1Phone: (506) 453-2844Fax: (506) 453-2106
Email: mphec@mphec.ca
Notification of Disclosure of Personal Information to Statistics Canada
The federal Statistics Act provides the legal authority for Statistics Canada to obtain access to personal information held by Mount Saint Vincent University. The information may be used for statistical purposes only, and the confidentiality provisions of the Statistics Act prevent the information from being released in any way that would identify a student.
Students who do not wish to have their personally-identifying information submitted to MPHEC or Statistics Canada will notify Mount Saint Vincent University by contacting:
C/o The RegistrarMount Saint Vincent University166 Bedford HighwayHalifax NS B3M 2J6Phone: (902) 457-6419Fax: (902) 457-6498
Academic Note: This web-based calendar information is applicable for the 2020-2021 academic year which runs from September 01, 2020 to August 31, 2021.
For information on previous years, please consult the University Academic Calendars web page.
Copyright 2020 Mount Saint Vincent University. All Rights Reserved – Disclaimer
© 2020 MSVUDisclaimer
Sitemap
